Jace Browning

I build, customize, integrate, and teach engineering software tools. With degrees in computer engineering and computer science, I am familiar with software development across multiple industries on a variety of platforms. I've worked on products in the embedded, mobile, and web space, but my expertise is Python programming. Sharing knowledge and active involvement in the local tech community are integral parts of my life and career.

Experience

Modustri Grand Rapids, MI

Quality Assurance and DevOps Lead

Apr 2015 - 2016

Managed testing and releases for a heavy-duty equipment inspection platform.

- Set up Continuous Integration for a Rails/Node/Python backend and iOS/Ember frontend
- Set up Continuous Deployment into dev/staging environments for all product components
- Exploratory Tested all new features and bug fixes using a GitHub pull request workflow
- Managed monthly production releases through an end-to-end test suite and deploy scripts

Adonit Grand Rapids, MI

Quality Assurance Lead

Oct 2014 - Mar 2015

Created the process and tooling necessary to bring a complex iPad sketching and ideation app to production and reach Editor's Choice with more than 250k users.

- Proposed and trained the team on optimal GitHub code review and branching strategies
- Configured and maintained a TeamCity CI server with multiple provisioned build agents
- Developed Python and Shell scripts to automate builds, testing, and static analysis

DornerWorks Grand Rapids, MI

Software Engineer

Oct 2013 - Oct 2014

Developed and tested products for several clients to quality standards set by their applicable regulatory industries. Reworked the entire internal Python development stack to promote automation.

- Automated traceability checks between requirements of a cockpit display system
- Deployed an extension to the Buildbot CI framework for desktop and embedded software
- Developed a Python framework to automate the testing of a VxWorks-based medical device

Johnson Controls, Inc.

Holland, MI

Software Engineer

May 2011 - Oct 2013

Technical lead for two production releases of vehicle Bluetooth audio systems. Mentored a dozen entry through senior-level engineers developing HMI software on an embedded Linux platform. Developed an array of tools to facilitate proper software testing and version control practices.

- Created a GUI to simulate infotainment applications from design specifications
- Initiated a team-wide investigation to replace an outdated version control system
- Designed a Python framework to emulate UI interaction for integration testing

Eaton Aerospace

Grand Rapids, MI

Software Engineer

May 2007 - May 2011

Involved in the entire airborne software lifecycle compliant with RTCA DO-178B standards. Led development and testing of a post-certification software release of a fly-by-wire flap system.

- Met a tight production schedule while eliminating one third of the defect backlog
- Built multiple Python applications to automate aircraft maintenance and troubleshooting

Education

Grand Valley State University

Grand Rapids, MI

Computer Science, M.S.

2010 - 2013

- 3.9 GPA
- Emphasis on distributed computing, mobile technologies, and requirements management
- Charter member of West Michigan Tau Beta Pi and GVSU Engineering alumni chapters

Grand Valley State University

Grand Rapids, MI

Computer Engineering, B.S.

2005 - 2009

- 3.7 GPA
- Honors College and Tau Beta Pi member
- Awarded Outstanding Senior Project and Outstanding Computer Engineering Graduate